Hugo Tunius - CV

I am a versatile developer with a passion for all things programming and design. I acquire new knowledge at a very rapid pace. Due to this I have built a vast understanding of and experience in many areas of modern development. With a solid foundation in Computer Science I have gathered experience throughout my personal and professional life in all parts of the stack. I thrive in an environment where I am allowed to work with a lot of individual responsibility on tasks that span multiple platforms, languages, and frameworks, while gaining knowledge in areas I am not yet familiar with.

Website: www.hugotunius.se

Github: @k0nserv

Phone: +4673 764 53 05

Skype: kOnserv

Email: h@tunius.se

Core Skills







Ruby



iOS



Web



MySQL



Sketch

Professional Experience

Developer - FishBrain

January 2014 - August 2015(Present)

FishBrain is the world's leading social network for recreational fishing with over one million users. I started as the first employed developer working on the iOS application, but quickly expanded to work on the backend and web properties in addition. I took the lead on converting the legacy PHP based XMLRPC API to a new REST API built with Ruby on Rails. Early on I additionally had responsibilities including server provisioning, monitoring and maintenance as well as helping out with design and product decisions. FishBrain employs a micro service architecture which gave me the opportunity to work on systems written in Go and Node.js. When we hired more people I was responsible for technology interviews and worked with new hires teaching Ruby and Rails.

Business Area Manager IT - Chalmers Teknologkonsulter

September 2012 - January 2014

Chalmers Tekonlogkonsulter is a company that provides consultancy services in all areas which are taught at Chalmers University. Its entire staff is made up of students from Chalmers who work while studying. I started as a consultant within the business area IT and Technology. I worked on several project ranging from iOS applications, to Ruby on Rails and C++ desktop programming. I also worked with sales by doing cold calls, attending meetings with potential and existing clients, and crafting project suggestions. I took on internal work and for a period had the role of marketing manager working with our digital presence and companywide design. During my last 7 months I held the role of Business Area Manager for the IT business area with responsibilities managing existing projects, new hires, strategy, sales leads and the consultants.

Summer Intern - Learning Well AB

June 2013 - August 2013

During my second summer at LearningWell I worked with frontend Javascript and backend C# in MVC4 in development of a logistics system. I also worked with Javascript and Node.js building a real time event notification system with critical time constraints using Socket.io

Summer Intern - Learning Well AB

June 2012 - September 2012

At LearningWell I developed an iOS application focused on news analytics, aggregation and mapping. I also helped out with IIS configuration and documentation.

IT Consultant - Diagumsbacken AB

January 2009 - December 2011

In this large project building a system, which is the core of the client's business, I worked with PHP, MySQL and frontend web with a friend. I worked part-time on this project during most of upper secondary school and it served me well as my first professional experience as a developer. Throughout the project I learnt technologies and tools, many of which were new to me, while delivering result to the client and managing my schoolwork. The systems handles everything ranging from the absolute core of the client's business to reporting, statistics and invoicing.

Education

Bachelor in Computer Science - Gothenburg University

September 2011 - December 2014(2.5 years, no degree)

I studied Computer Science at Gothenburg University. A program I picked due to the freedom and high focus on individual choices. The program lets its students build their own program by tailoring their courses in the second and third year. This appealed to me as it would allow me to focus on the areas of Computer Science that truly was of interest to me.

I mainly picked courses that were heavily theoretical because I am of the opinion that practical skills can be better learnt in environments other than school while theoretical skills are easier to obtain in school.

IT and Technology - Nyköpings gymnasium

September 2008 - June 2011

Upper secondary school where I built a lot of my interest in programming.

Other

Core Contributor - CocoaPods

Cocoapods is the leading dependency manager for iOS and OSX development. It is written in Ruby and includes a CLI tool and several backend services that support it. I have found great joy in working on a tool that I use every day and that is so important in day to day work on the iOS and OSX platform.

Languages

Swedish - Naitive proficiency English - Bilingual proficiency

References

Available on request